From the 2024.2 version, the settings related to the thickness of the board are all put together, including the new functions.
The overall operation will be smoother.
In the property editor, a new set of categories has been added.
The thickness rendering function has to be moved here to increase the thickness of the board by a relatively large rendering thickness.
To ensure that the thickness of the board can be seen only when it is located on the surface of the dense texture.
Squeeze out direction option
You can set the direction of the thickness of the board.
The default squeeze out direction is all.
At this time, the thickness will be displayed on the front and back of the board.
The squeeze out direction can be changed to before or after.
You can make the thickness of the board only exist on the front or back of the board.
Here, change back to all.
Whether to select the front and back can be displayed or hide the back and front of the board.
Open the default.
Open the display.
This is the grid.
Hide the front.
Hide the back.
The sewing area can be controlled.
The grid on the side of the board shows that the default is closed.
The sides of the two boards have been sewed.
The grid on the sewing area is related to the total thickness of the board.
The total thickness of the board is.
The thickness of the material itself.
The thickness is Vince.
The thickness on the board.
You can choose the corresponding fabric on the material window.
Then good in the property editor.
Found the bottom of the thickness.
This material has a thickness of 0.5.
Thickness selection board.
In the property editor.
You can see the corresponding thickness.
The thickness of the board.
If the total thickness is equal, then the side mesh of the seam allowance will be hidden.
The thickness of this panel is also set to 10.
Pull the panel a little bit.
We can see that the side mesh of the seam allowance is hidden.
At this time,
Open or close the display of the seam allowance.
The mesh of the side seam allowance can be displayed or hidden.
The panel on this side is also the same.
This is in the case of equal total thickness.
So if the total thickness is not equal,
Choose a panel.
Increase the thickness of its seam allowance to 11.
This panel is relatively thick.
Its side mesh is not hidden.
The side mesh of the relatively thin panel is hidden.
Pull the panel a little bit.
This is due to the different thickness of the seam allowance.
When the panel is changed to the same thickness of the seam allowance,
Let this panel apply another fabric.
The thickness of this fabric is default 0.5.
Change to 0.6.
The effect that appears is the same as before.
The side mesh of the relatively thick panel has been displayed.
At this time, open or close the seam allowance.
The mesh has been displayed.
And this relatively thin panel
Can be displayed freely or hide the side mesh.
As before,
You can adjust the side mesh of the panel by adjusting the value of the curve.
Turn off the display mesh first.
Adjust the curve.
The curve on the side of the panel changes with time.
Open the display mesh again.
Restore the curve.
Detail level controls the number of divisions of the side mesh.
Change to 2.
The side has only two layers of mesh.
You can freely enter the number between 1 to 10 here.
The double-layer performance of the panel is also here.
Next, I will show you the use of the four applications.
See the right pocket of the coat.
This kind of single line pocket.
We would like to make this effect.
That is, the panel of the lip.
A little lower than the panel of the body.
Then we can use the output direction function.
Achieve this effect.
Select the lip panel of the left pocket.
To make it face out.
Then select the output direction.
After that,
You can make the lip face in.
The panel of the body is set to the output direction.
The front.
It is equivalent to raising the body.
This is the effect from the side.
Switch to 3D and 2D display.
Select the seam line of the lip and the front piece.
Change to reverse.
Select the seam line B.
At this time, the effect is more obvious.
See the inner top of the t-shirt.
You can also operate it like this.
The output direction of the panel of the lip is set to the back.
The front of the t-shirt is set to the front.
You can already see the effect from the side.
Finally, select the seam line of the lip.
You can change it to one,
Or,
You can move the part of the lip just like this.
At this time,
The lip of the lipelions in front of the sir.
You can try to align the上 along the side of the lip.
Move the lip in the opposite direction.
The model surface of the model in this file is 0.
Select the shoulder strap. The conflict thickness of the shoulder strap plate is 2.
Change to 1 and then simulate.
The gap becomes smaller.
Return to the state of conflict thickness as 2.
In some cases, the conflict thickness cannot be changed.
At this time, you can use the squeeze direction to optimize the performance of the shoulder strap.
That is, the squeeze direction of the shoulder strap plate is changed to one side of the model body.
If you are not sure about the front and back of the plate, switch to the black and white surface.
White front, gray back.
Switch back to the thick texture surface.
The opposite side of the shoulder strap plate faces the model.
Change the squeeze direction to .
The shoulder strap is close to the model.
The zipper of the shoulder strap and the single thread pocket in the front are the same operation.
Here is no more count.
In addition, when making accessories, you can also use the squeeze direction.
To achieve some specific effects.
Now I want to make a concave effect on the shoulder strap.
You should think about the different thickness of the shoulder strap plate.
The shoulder strap plate is set to .
From the front, the effect is not bad.
But when you turn to the back, you will find that there is also a concave line on the back.
If you want to keep the back flat.
Only the front has a concave line.
All the squeeze directions of the shoulder strap are changed to .
At this time, the back is flat.
Select the self-made shoulder strap.
Also apply white fabric.
There is no trace on the back.
This is the front.
The front is this effect.
I look forward to exploring more ways of use.